

# R//R

# RAFAEL REIS

Software Developer

# **⊗** CONTACTS

ADDRESS
TORONTO ON
M6P 2M8

PHONE +55 65 984463703

RAFAEL.REIS14@OUTLOOK.COM

# SOCIAL MEDIA

#### LINKEDIN

LINKEDIN.COM/IN/RAFAELREISDEV

#### **GITHUB**

GITHUB.COM/RAFAELREIS14

#### **PERSONAL WEBPAGE**

HTTPS://RAFAELREIS14.GITHUB.IO/

# PROFILE

Hello! My name is Rafael Reis. I am Software Developer with 10+ years developing and delivering different kinds of applications using a variety of languages and platforms. Team leader working in agile development environments using different methodologies. Excellent communicator experienced in understanding customer's needs. Results-oriented, resourceful and problem-solving software developer professional specializing in large-scale software design and development for a wide variety of companies. High level of involvement and adherence to best practice.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### 2012 - Now O TODIMO

#### Software Developer:

- Responsible to idealize and development Todimo's app which allows sellers making orders using their phone integrating with the main database, making the process faster and increasing sales. The customers were also able to use the app, which provides them vouchers based on past purchases to apply in futures purchases.
- Created a framework and components to help developers with common development tasks reducing project times, budgets and improving deliverable quality.
- Responsible for integrating several internal software.
- Maintain, improve and develop new features of all software
- Responsible for training, solving complex problems and helping other developers by removing their impediments.
- Technologies: Delphi Xe2 and Xe10, Angular 2+, Ionic 2+, .Net, C#, Asp.Net, JavaScript, HTML, SQL Server, RESTFul, SOAP, Entity FrameWork, SQL Server (Desktop, Web Applications and DLL).

#### 2012 O AMAGGI

#### Software Developer:

- Maintain, improve and develop new features of all software
- Implemented a software responsible for monitoring the company's phone calls reducing costs, rework, and errors.
- Technologies: Delphi 7, C#, Asp.Net, PLSQL, Oracle

#### 2010-2011 O DATA MANAGER

#### Scrum Master / Software Developer:

- Responsible for planning, executing and controlling the projects scopes
- Responsible for control risks and preventive and corrective actions, planning and control schedule of deadlines reducing change requests
- Responsible to ensure the project's efficacy, manage the team and the communication between the parties reducing rework;
- Responsible to encourage integration between team members, customers and other employees of the company
- Manage all the commitments agreed on during the project.
- Responsible to ensure that all procedures are being followed and monitor all stages of projects.
- Systems Analyst in charge of planning, implementing, developing all projects using Agile SCRUM;

**Technologies**: Delphi 7, Java (framework), PLSQL, Oracle.



Delphi 7, Xe2 and Xe10 .Net, C#, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Frame Work, LINQ, JQuery Angular 2, Type Script, HTML5, Ionic 2, Cordova OOD, Design Patternrs, UML Relational Database (Sql Server) NoSql Database (Firebase) Java **Source Control** (Sourcesafe, Github, Subversion) **Project Management** (SCRUM, PMBOK) Web Service (Rest, Soap)

2008-2010 O SUPERIOR COURT OF JUSTICE OF MATO GROSSO Software Developer:

- Maintain, improve and develope new features of all software • Implemented a virtual judgment module, helping to increase the
- productivity of judges by speeding up the trial of lawsuits. With this, the Court of Justice of the State of Mato Grosso, was awarded nationally for the agility in the trial of processes conquered through the module of virtual judgment.
- Worked on the new architecture and implementation of a unique judicial system that was adopted by more than 10 states in Brazil.
- Designed an integrated software using Webservice REST/SOAP in order to collect data from different application of the government
- Provided training across organization to users and technicians.
- Technologies: .Net, C#, Asp.Net, JavaScript, HTML, SQL Server, REST/SOAP, Entity FrameWork, SQL Server

# **EDUCATION**

2011 - 2013 O MAS TER OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

Fundacao Getulio Vargas - FGV: MAB in Project Management

2009 - 2010 O POST GRADUATION

University of Cuiaba: Project Management and Software Quality

2001 - 2004 O BACHELORES DEGREE

UNIRONDON: Computer and Information Science

## LANGUAGUES

O PORTUGUESE

Native

o ENGLISH

Full professional proficiency